<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Programming on dbordeR</title>
    <link>http://localhost:5163/categories/programming/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Programming on dbordeR</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2015 21:49:20 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:5163/categories/programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Social Determinants of health</title>
      <link>http://localhost:5163/blog/2015/10/02/sde/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2015 21:49:20 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:5163/blog/2015/10/02/sde/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;esperanza-de-vida-y-condiciones-económicas-en-américa-latina-en-medio-siglo&#34;&gt;Esperanza de vida y condiciones económicas en América Latina en medio siglo.&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:5163/img/p.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;diabetes-y-la-epidemida-de-padecimientos-crónicos-degenerativos-además-un-padecimiento-considerado-como-de-alto-impacto-financiero-para-el-sector-salud-mexicano-en-el-corto-plazo&#34;&gt;Diabetes y la epidemida de padecimientos crónicos degenerativos. Además un padecimiento considerado como de alto impacto financiero para el sector salud Mexicano en el corto plazo.&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The evolution of type II diabetes as a death cause in Mexico increased by 76% during&#xA;the period between 1998-2013, while the over all death causes experienced a 18,3%&#xA;increase in same period. The exponential growth rate implicit by this trend reflects a&#xA;public health concern of epidemic proportions.&#xA;Although diabetes is a major public health problem in Mexico previously thought to be&#xA;related to population with relative higher income levels or affluent, recent studies had&#xA;suggested an epidemiological transition impacting individuals in lower income regions.&#xA;Studies conducted with a focus on the Mexican population suggest that this transition&#xA;may be linked to nutritional changes (Seuring, Goryakin &amp;amp; Suhrcke, 2015). Argument&#xA;that highlights the importance to consider social determinants of health such as&#xA;consumption patterns as contextual factors to understand this growing public health&#xA;treat.&#xA;Studies emphasizing behavioral determinants have established that inadequate diet is&#xA;a key risk factor for the development of T2D (Sundquist, Eriksson, Mezuk &amp;amp; Ohlsson,&#xA;2015; Wali, Thomas &amp;amp; Sutherland, 2014). According to Ortiz-Hernández (2006), a link&#xA;towards diabetes development through consumption practices finds a key path via the&#xA;metabolic energy intake balance; the path identified can be traced back to life style&#xA;habits further pressured by low price per calories processed foods available at the&#xA;neighborhood scale.&#xA;As evidence suggest, diet follow trends tied to consumption practices that differ across&#xA;demographic groups and regions (Gordon-Larsen, Guilkey and Popkin, 2011). Although&#xA;it is recognized that T2D is a multifactorial public health issue and its determinants are&#xA;not limited to consumption patterns, considering contextual factors may provide&#xA;additional insights to improve its understanding at a regional scale.&#xA;Despite the importance of geographic location to explain this epidemic, in the past&#xA;decades the study of biological risk factors has been the dominant paradigm (Graves&#xA;and Kayal, 2008; Stolar 2010). While research on environmental correlates of physical&#xA;activity such as obesity, a well-known risk factor for the development of diabetes (Day&#xA;and Baily, 2011) has been well documented in the US Mexico border communities&#xA;(Fisher-Hoch et al., 2010). There is a clear research gap relative to diabetes studies for&#xA;the Mexican southern border states and its connections to population consumption&#xA;patterns at a local level.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Internatinal Migration and Water Scarcity</title>
      <link>http://localhost:5163/blog/2015/09/17/internatinal-migration/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2015 13:47:08 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:5163/blog/2015/09/17/internatinal-migration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Historically, causes of international migration have been a dominant research area on the international migration research agenda; socioeconomic determinants such as income and poverty conditions have been extensively documented as they represent common motives for the movement of people across borders around the world. However, until recently, less attention has been directed to environmental determinants of international migration. Yet, as migration patterns themselves have become more complex, the environmental dimension has been gaining attention after the recognition of the possible effects of changing climate conditions and the increasing possibility of experiencing extreme weather events (IOM, 2009).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
